Simon Wang | Toronto, ON | Tel: 647-519-3766

Email: mtwangyugeng@gmail.com | Web: mtwangyugeng.github.io/personalpage

GitHub: github.com/mtwangyugeng | Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/yu-geng-wang-474553192

Summary

Recent graduate with CS and Math Major. I have strong knowledge (8/10) of software fundamentals such as data structures, algorithm design, design patterns in object-oriented programming. I also used (5/10) functional programming and operating system fundamentals for my projects. I have many experiences in Agile development projects in academic settings. I have demonstrated that I can lead/manage scrums under Agile methodologies.

I have a strong interest in design patterns, mathematical/coding challenges, and UI designing.

Relevant Experience

Open source, **Large Software System**, **Python**: Participated in an open-source contribution simulation for the python library matplotlib (Jan 2019 - Mar 2019):

- Took on the position of scrum master for two working weeks, following agile development process and meeting minutes
- Provide feasible and TA-endorsed solutions for an issue label "Hard" in the known issues
- Wrote reports on the object-oriented design patterns and open-source contribution processes of matplotlib
- Provided detailed reports, manual, and convincing acceptance/ unit tests for the issues we have chosen to contribute.

UX Design, Communication: Led a group of four to design a new interface for Toad for Oracle (April 2018 - Aug 2018)

- Interviewed two Database Management software users for our data gathering and rolled out details for user requirements
- Gathered Data (with interviews and artifacts) from potential clients
- Created GUI prototype and tutorials using interactive elements of PowerPoint
- Evaluated our interface prototype based on the traversing times and user feedbacks

Fast Learner, Ul/Graphic Design, Web Development: Developed two React web apps for personal projects and Hackathon events (Dec 2020 - Jan 2021):

- Created reusable React components that can be used in other projects and by other people interested in React.js
- Creating cool and interactive CSS animations with CSS transitions and animations
- Used graphic design apps to make cool badges for people who helped me develop the project
- Used Node.js and Socket.io to run a chat server for my chatbox React component
- For more information, check out my webpage: mtwangyugeng.github.io/personalpage

Agile and MySQL: Participated in the course project contest with a group of five; Using an agile development cycle, we developed an application for statistics students and instructors to manage their work. (Oct 2017 - Dec 2017)

- Made up user stories and tasks based on the client's needs and used spreadsheets to manage tasks weekly
- Developed the front end of the app using Java's JSwing library
- Learned and linked the MySQL database APIs to the front end
- Achieved 4.0 in GPA for this project

Education

University of Toronto Scarborough Campus (UTSC)

September 2014 - November 2019

Graduate - Honours Bachelor of Science (BS)
Major in Computer Science and Major in Mathematics